<items>
		<item>
			<date>1750</date>
			<title>Incident Touches off War</title>
			<desc>A savage war with the Cherokees was touched off after an incident at Ft. Prince where an English Army officer was wounded. Cherokee hostages were killed in cold blood and all hope For negotiations ended.</desc>
			<img>/revolution/images/cherokee.jpg</img>
			<img-cap>Image of the Cherokee</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>April 1760</date>
			<title>British Army Arrives to Protect Province</title>
			<desc>Gov. William Bull Jr. requests help. About 1,200 british regulars arived under Col. Archibald Montgomery. They relieved Ft. Prince aFter a campaign of burning villages. Montgomery then was ordered back north leaving a small Force For local defense.</desc>
			<img>/revolution/images/britishArmy.jpg</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>1751</date>
			<title>British Send Troops Again</title>
			<desc>When Fort Loudoun surrendered to the Cherokees, many of the garrison were killed and the rest taken prisoner. This reopening of the war prompted another request for help. Col. James Grant responded with 1,600 men under his command. A force of over 1,000 provincials joined with these British regulars and eventually defeated the Cherokees.</desc>
			<img></img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>1753</date>
			<title>War Doubles Britan's Debt. Colonies Asked to Pay Their Share</title>
			<desc>The conclusion of the French and Indian War, or Seven Years War, resulted in a definite change in British-colonial relations. The Treaty of Paris in 1763 affirmed Britain's undisputed control of the seas and shipping trade. It also affirmed its sovereignty over much of the North American continent east of the Mississippi River. However, the British had gone deeply in debt to finance the war. Having borrowed heavily From British and Dutch bankers the national debt almost doubled From £75 million in 1754 to £133 million in 1763. To raise the necessary funds to retire the debt British officials turned to increasing import duties and taxes on goods like sugar, tobacco, salt, beer, spirits, etc. Given that a portion of the debt was due to Britain defending the North American colonies during the war, the British government felt that the colonies were obligated to share the costs of defending the empire.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>


		<item>
			<date>April 23,1763</date>
			<title>John Wilkes Jailed For Criticizing King</title>
			<desc>John Wilkes, notorious and popular champion of liberty in England, anonymously denounces a passage of a speech by King George through an article in No. 45 of The North Briton. Wilkes writes that the speech was "the most abandoned instance of ministerial effrontery ever attempted to be imposed on mankind," and implies that the King had been persuaded to continue a lie. A warrant was issued For the arrest of the article's author, the printer and publishers of the paper, and for the seizure of their papers. Wilkes was imprisoned without permission to see legal counsel or friends but was eventually freed through the efforts of powerful friends.</desc>
			<img>/revolution/images/johnWilkes.jpg</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>February 21, 1764</date>
			<title>Pitt's Plea Fails to Help Wilkes</title>
			<desc>Despite Williarn Pitt's efforts to protect the liberty of the press by defending John Wilkes' right to publish opinions against the government. Nevertheless, Wilkes is outlawed for refusing to stand trial for libel. He had reprinted the North Briton, and distributed an obscene poem ridiculing prominent people.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>1768</date>
			<title>Wilkes Expelled From House of Commons</title>
			<desc>John Wilkes, after returning From exile, is elected to Parliament From Middlesex by an enormous majority. When he is imprisoned under the old sentence, mobs threaten the public peace. From jail he carries on a campaign against the government which gets him expelled From the British House of Commons. He was reelected three times but was reFused a seat. On the fourth election the House ignores him and declares his opponent the victor.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>October 1, 1768</date>
			<title>South Carolina Celebrates Wilkes' 45th</title>
			<desc>After Charleston mechanics hold a nominating caucus For an upcoming election to the South Carolina Assembly they hold a celebration honoring John Wilkes's denouncement of the king in No. 45 of The North Briton. The meeting begins with Forty-Five rockets being fired at the Liberty Tree, which itself was decorated with Forty-Five lights. The Liberty Tree being on the outskirts of town, the procession then marched to town, down King Street on to Broad until reaching Dillon's tavern. At the tavern Forty-Five lights were placed on the table, with Forty-Five bowls of punch, Forty-Five bottles of wine and ninety-two glasses.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>Dec 8, 1769</date>
			<title>South Carolina Supports Wilkes' Legal Defense</title>
			<desc>In support of John Wilkes, the South Carolina Assembly votes to send £1,500 [sterling] to the Society of the Bill of Rights in England, Wilkes' defense fund in England.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
		<date>April 1770</date>
			<title>Wilkes Released from Prision</title>
			<desc>John Wilkes is released from prison. In Charlestown, about 100 members of the Club No. 45 celebrate.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>April 14,177O</date>
			<title>SC Assembly Denied Authority to Raise Funds</title>
			<desc>George III, outraged after hearing about South Carolina's contribution to the Wilkes fund, orders his government to send out additional instructions which deny the authority of the Assembly to appropriate funds for such a purpose. These instructions also reaffirm the authority of the Royal Council to amend and/or pass money bills For the colony. The ensuing impasse keeps the Assembly From doing any real business For the remainder of the colonial period.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
			

		<item>
			<date>March 22, 1765</date>
			<title>Colonies Taxed Through Stamp Act</title> 
			<desc>The English Parliament passes the Stamp Act. It is the first direct tax to be levied on the American colonies and requires all newspapers, pamphlets, real estate transactions, bills of sale, marriage licenses, wills and inheritance papers, playing cards, advertisements, etc. to bear a stamp. Revenue derived From the sale of stamps is to be used to finance colonial defense.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>August 2, 1765</date>
			<title>Colonies Seek Unity Against Stamp Act</title>
			<desc>Local leaders endorse the proposal by Massachusetis For a Stamp Act Congress. They elect Thomas Lynch, John Rutledge, and Christopher Gadsden to attend. According to the South-Carolina Gazette, the purpose of the Congress is to discuss the difficulties the colonies are suffering due to the Stamp Act and to “consider of a general, united, dutiful, loyal, and humble representation of their condition to His Majesty and the Parliament and to implore relief."'</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>November 29, 1765</date>
			<title>Assembly Adopts Gadsdens Critical Report</title>
			<desc>The Commons House of Assembly adopts, by an almost unanimous vote, the report of Gadsden's committee which set forth the rights and responsibilities of English subjecis. Of the all the members of the House, only William Wragg objects to the report.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>February 1766</date>
			<title>Shipping Disrupted Due to Controversy</title>
			<desc>Charlestown's harbor is congested with ships unable to leave due to the colonists refusal to use properly stamped clearance papers. As a result about 1,400 sailors are stranded in port, one-fourth the city's population.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>March 1766</date>
			<title>Stamp Act Repealed</title>
			<desc>Having realized that the Stamp Act was unenforcible and fearing economic disruption over the controversy, Parliament repeals the tax. William Pitt becomes a hero to the colonists for his efforts in Parliament on their behalf.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>May 3, 1766</date>
			<title>Charlestown Celebrates Repeal of Stamp Act</title>
			<desc>News of the repeal of the Stamp Act reaches Charlestown, resulting in a celebration held that night. On May 6, 1766 a notice appeared in the South-Carolina Gazette describing local reaction.</desc>
			<img>ADD LINK ON SLIDE 7 AS IMG</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>June 20, 1766</date>
			<title>King Praised For "Great Goodness"</title>
			<desc>The South Carolina Commons House of Assembly thanks the king in no uncertain terms For his "great goodness and condescension in hearing the petition of your American subjects, and gratiously relieving them by the repeal of the Stamp Act.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>May 31, 1770</date>
			<title>Pitt Statue Arrives in Charlestown</title>
			<desc>A statue of William Pitt, designed by Joseph Wilton, arrives from London. It is considered to be the oldest portrait statue in America and possibly the First commemorating a public figure in America.</desc>
			<img>10-B</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>

		<item>
			<date>Spring 1765</date>
			<title>Gadsden: "Liberty or Death"</title>
			<desc>In the local press, Christopher Gadsden attacks attempts to enforce the Stamp Act. He calls for continued resistance by saying, "Aut mors aut Libertas," ("Liberty or Death").</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>October 18, 1765</date>
			<title>Mobs Discourage Stamp Use</title>
			<desc>While the Stamp Act Congress is meeting in New York, the ship Planter's Adventure arrives during the night with stamps, stamped paper, and a stamp officer aboard. Early the next morning, an effigy of the stamp officer is suspended from gallows at the corner of Broad and Church streets. Inscribed on the gallows are the words "Liberty and No Stamp Act." Attached to the figure is the notice: "Whoever shall dare attempt to pull down these effigies had better been born with a millstone about his neck and be cast into the sea." For the next eight or nine days armed mobs search Charlestown homes For stamped paper until Royal Lt. Gov. Bull posts a notice in the local paper that "the stamps lately arrived were lodged in Fort Johnson till it should be necessary to remove them thence."</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>Fall 1766</date>
			<title>Gadsden Calls For Independence</title>
			<desc>Christopher Gadsden addresses a large gathering under the Liberty Tree, warning against the folly of believing that Britain would withdraw her claims of dominion over the colony's affairs. He asserts that they should be prepared to work towards "absolute independence or a state approaching a confederation." A later account by Dr. Joseph Johnson reported that the address was received with profound silence and that a group linked hands and pledged to resist in every possible way. The group making the pledge included Christopher Gadsden, William Johnson, Joseph Verree, John Gullerton, James Brown, Nathaniel Lebby, George Flagg, Thomas Coleman, John Hall, William Field, John Lawton, Uz Rogers, John Calvert, Henrv Bookless, J. Barlow, Tunis Tebout, Peter Munclear, Wiliam Trusler, Robert Hower, Alexander Alexander, Edward Wevman, Thomas Searl, William Loughton, Daniel Cannon, and Benjamin Hawes.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>July 3, 1767</date>
			<title>Charlestown Agrees to Non-Importation Plan</title>
			<desc>The tradesmen, also called mechanics, of Charlestown gather under the "Liberty Tree" to protest English trade policy. They set up a committee to discuss the non-importation of English goods. On the following day they met again to listen to the report of the committee and eventually agreed to the non-importation proposal.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>August 16, 1771</date>
			<title>Differing Opinions about England Lead to Violence</title>
			<desc>A duel takes place in a local tavern, during which John Haley, a local doctor and Patriot, kills Peter Delancy, a Tory From New York. The duel was sparked by opposing opinions about England. On Aug. 27, a proclamation was issued in the South Carolina Gazette and Country Journal by William Bull, the Lieutenant-Governor of South Carolina: "Whereas I have received Information that John Haley, of Charles-Town, Practitioner in Physic, did, in the Evening of the 15th instant, feloniously kill and slay Peter DeLancy, Esq.; at the House of William Holliday, in Charles-Town; and that the said John Haly hath, since absconded, and Fled From Justice: In order that he may be Amenable thereto, I have thought fit, by and with the Advice and Consent of his Majesty's Honourable Council, to issue this my Proclarnation, Hereby strictly enjoining and requiring all his Majesty's Justices, Constables, Peace-officers, and other his Majesty's Liege Subjects, to Use their utmost Endeavours, to apprehend, or Cause to be apprehended the said John Haly, wheresoever he may be found within the said Province...”</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>October 8 - 10, 1772</date>
			<title>Governor Moves Assembly</title>
			<desc>Montague calls the Assembly to meet in BeauFort. He hopes that this move will allow him to control the Assembly by removing the influence of the Charlestown patriots but the attempt fails.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>


		<item>
			<date>1767</date>
			<title>Parliament Passes Townsend Taxes</title>
			<desc>Townsend Acts. Charles Townsend, Chancellor of the Exchequer since 1766, leads Parliarnent to cut the British land tax and to offset the cuts by taxing the Americans through a series of acts called the Townsend Duties or Acts. The money that was collected was used to pay the salaries of British colonial officials in an effort to make these officials independent of colonial legislatures and therefore better able to enforce British orders and laws.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>May-June 1767</date>
			<title>Ships Seized For Improper Papers</title>
			<desc>British colonial officials confiscate vessels carrying goods such as rice, lumber, etc. From Carolina plantations to market without properly filed customs papers. British officials contend they are enforcing the Navigation Acts. South Carolina merchants are concerned that corrupt officials will enforce the acts and seize their vessels for personal gain  One of the major disagreements between the British authorities and the Carolina merchants occurs when the sloop Active is seized by Capt. James Hawker of HMS Sardoine.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>June 1767</date>
			<title>Laurens and Leigh: War with Words</title>
			<desc>British authorities confiscate two ships owned by Henry Laurens, the sloops Wambaw and Broughton Island, over a dispute with the Collector of His Majesty's Customs for Charlestown. Henry Laurens, a prominent South Carolina plantation owner and merchant, and Vice-Admiral Judge Egerton Leigh enter into a venornous pamphlet controversy.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>February 1768</date>
			<title>Massachusetis Urges Townsend Repeal</title>
			<desc>The Massachusetis House of Representatives, at the urging of Samuel Adams, passed the Massachusetts Circular Letter which attack Parliament's persistence in taxing the colonies without proper representation and urges other colonial legislatures to pass petitions calling on Parliarnent to repeal the Townsend Acts.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>November 19, 1768</date>
			<title>Assembly Dissolved For Opposing Townsend Acts</title>
			<desc>Twenty-six members of the Assembly vote unanimously to endorse the Massachusetts Circular Letter. As a result of this vote, the Royal Governor would soon dissolve the Assembly and the "unanimous twenty-six" becomes an important symbol in South Carolina's Revolutionary movement.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>July 22,1769</date>
			<title>Non-Importation Policy Outlined</title>
			<desc>In order to enforce the Non-Importation Agreements, a committee of thirteen merchants, thirteen planters, and thirteen mechanics is established. The Non-Importantion Agreements are SC's official protests against the Townsend Duties passed by the English Parliament in 1767.</desc>
			<img>ADD 8B AS IMAGE</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>DEC. 13, 1770</date>
			<title>Colonial Unity Against England Breaks Down</title>
			<desc>Charlestown shops are empty and the slave trade has dwindled to nothing. Eager merchants and planters outvote the town's mechanics and SC opens up the port of Charlestown to commerce once again, breaking the non-importation agreements. This move is brought upon by news that the northern colonies had already broken the agreement and were again accepting trade with Britain. James Parsons, John Rutledge, Peter Manigault, Charles Pinckney, and John Macklain are elected to a committee to “draw up a proper Protest, in the name and on the behalf of the People of South-Carolina against the conduct of the Northern Colonies.”</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>


		<item>
			<date>December 2, 1773</date>
			<title>Merchants Agree to Not Sell Taxed Tea</title>
			<desc>The London "anchors before the town" with 257 chests of tea upon which the controversial tax was to be charged. A committee of citizens gather and convince the merchants to whom the tea was to be sold not to pay the tax. The merchants agree not to accept or sell the tea. The committee advises Alexander Curling, the captain of the ship which brought the tea From the East India Company in London, to keep the tea on board his ship and to take it back to England. At issue is whether Parliament has the right to tax the colonists.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>December 9, 1773</date>
			<title>S.C. Group Forms 1st Chamber of Commerce</title>
			<desc>"Gentlemen in Trade" led by Miles Brenton, John Savage, and David Deas meet at Mrs. Swallows Tavern at Broad and Church Streets. They agree to form a Chamber of Commerce, the First in America to oppose the non-exportation movement.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>December 22, 1773</date>
			<title>British officials Seize Tea Shipment</title>
			<desc>The captain of the London receives anonymous threats that unless the ship is moved into deeper water it will be burned. A confrontation is avoided when the shipment is seized by British officials. The time had elapsed in which the duty for the tea must be paid and it therefore became the property of the “Collector of His Majesty's Customs.” It is brought onshore and is stored in the basement of the recently-built Exchange Building. The tea lay in the storehouse For nearly three years until it is sold to purchase war material for South Carolina.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>June 1774</date>
			<title>Boston Harbor Closed in Retaliation</title>
			<desc>News arrives that the King and Parliament with the passage of the Boston Port Act had closed Boston harbor until the costs of the destroyed tea and its duties had been paid. The Massachusetts Government Act altered the colony's charter thereby reasserting Parliament's control of the colonies.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>July 6, 1774</date>
			<title>Charlestonians Send Aid to Boston</title>
			<desc>Charlestonians send help to Bostonians in the form of money and 200 barrels of rice. The gesture is a response to the British closure of the Boston port over the "tea incident"</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>November 3, 1774</date>
			<title>Tea Dumped into Charlestown Harbor</title>
			<desc>As a protest against the tea tax, the seven chests of tea From the Magna Carta are dumped into Charlestown Harbor by the merchants who were supposed to have sold them. Sympathetic citizens nearby encourage this act of deﬁance.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>December 1, 1774</date>
			<title>Non-Importation Agreement Goes Into effect</title>
			<desc>The continental non-importation agreement, created by the Continental Congress, goes into effect.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>


		<item>
			<date>December 3, 1773</date>
			<title>First Anti-tea General Meeting Held</title>
			<desc>The first of a series of General Meetings was held in the Exchange Building. Members of the Assembly as well as mechanics and others attended to discuss colonial response to British taxes on tea. This group eventually organized the Provincial Congress which in turn became the S.C. State Government.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>July 6-8, 1774</date>
			<title>First Congressional Delegates Chosen</title>
			<desc>The delegates to the First Continental Congress are elected at a General Meeting of the people held in Charlestown. The delegates include: John Rutledge, Henry Middleton, Thomas Lynch, Edward Rutledge, and Christopher Gadsden.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>August 14, 1774</date>
			<title>Minister Dismissed For Supporting King</title>
			<desc>The assistant minister to St. Michael's, John Bullman, preaches against those who "censure the conduct of the king": his sermon angers Patriot members of the church and he is soon dismissed.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>October 22, 1774</date>
			<title>Henry Middleton Becomes President of Continental Congress</title>
			<desc>Henry Middleton of Charleston becomes president of the Continental Congress. The Congress soon petitions the king For redress of grievances and adopts a pledge to embargo most trade with Great Britain.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>


		<item>
			<date>June 8, 1775</date>
			<title>S.C. Loyalists Punished</title>
			<desc>Two Loyalists are seized by a crowd and accused of actively supporting the English cause. The two individuals are "stripped, tarred Feathered, and carted through the streets." An account of the event appeared in the South Carolina Gazette and Country Joumal June 13, 1775.</desc>
			<img>ADD 1B AS IMAGE</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>August-September, 1775</date>
			<title>Drayton and Tennent Travel to Back Country</title>
			<desc>William Henry Drayton and the Reverend William Tennent travel the backcountry, explaining the views held by patriots.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>August 18, 1775</date>
			<title>Thomas Jeremiah Hanged</title>
			<desc>A Free AFrican-American river pilot and slave owner named Thomas Jeremiah is hanged for offering to give aid to the British. He is also accused of planning a slave insurrection.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>November 10-21, 1775</date>
			<title>First Blood Shed Near Ninety-Six</title>
			<desc>Major Andrew Williamson and Major James Mayson with South Carolina Patriot militia were besieged in a stockaded fort erected at Savage's Old fort near Ninety Six by Loyalist forces under Major Joseph Robinson and Captain Patrick Cunningham. Both sides suffered casualties, and the indecisive fighting ended in a truce called on the evening  of November 21. --Lumpkin</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>December 23 - 30, 1775</date>
			<title>The Snow Campaign</title>
			<desc>After the successful December campaign against the Loyalists in the upcountry Colonel Richard Richardson's Patriot militia marched back to the Congaree River impeded on most of the route by fifteen inches of snow. The troops suffered heavily from exposure and frostbite. The operation was known thereafter as the Snow Campaign.  --Lumpkin</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>Dec 22, 1775</date>
			<title>Patriots Capture Loyalist Force</title>
			<desc>Colonel William "Danger" Thomson with 1,300 rangers and militiamen at the Great Canebreak on the Reedy River surprised and captured most of a Loyalist force operating in the area. Its leader, Captain Patrick Cunningham, deserted his men and escaped, riding a barebacked horse, to the Cherokee Nation. --Lumpkin </desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>February 13, 1777</date>
			<title>Loyalty Oath Creates Turmoil</title>
			<desc>The new state government passes an ordinance requiring every male citizen to take an oath denouncing the King and declaring loyalty to the state. The act states that "if any person refused to take this oath he should be sent From the State with his family to Europe or the West Indies at the public expense, except such that were able to pay their own, and that if any such person returned he would be adjudged guilty of treason against the State, and upon conviction should suffer death as a traitor." The announcement of this act is met with public outrage.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>January 15, 1778</date>
			<title>Loyalists Suspected of Setting Fire</title>
			<desc>A Fire breaks out near the intersection of Queen and Union (now known as State) streets. House after house along Queen Street is burned and spreads down Union Street to Broad Street and from there on to Elliott Street and Bedon's Alley, down the east side of Church Street to Stoll's Alley all of Tradd Street east of Church. Rumors circulate that the fire was set by British loyalists.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>


		<item>
			<date>April 14, 1775</date>
			<title>British Troops Sent to Enforce Colonial Policies</title>
			<desc>News arrives that Parliament has ignored the petitions of the Continental Congress petition for a redress of grievances and instead has supported the the king's request to send more troops to enforce his colonial policies.  Meanwhile, in the midst of the revolutionary fervor, powder and arms held in the public storehouses at Hobcaw, on Charlestown Neck, and at the State House are seized by citizens. In all, 800 guns, 200 cutlasses, and 1,600 lbs. of powder are taken.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item> 
		<item>
			<date>May 8, 1775</date>
			<title>Fighting Breaks Out in Massachusetts</title>
			<desc>News reaches Charlestown of fighting between American citizens and British soldiers in Lexington and Concord.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item> 
		<item>
			<date>June 14, 1775</date>
			<title>Council of Safety Selected to Prepare Military</title>
			<desc>In a move towards independence, the South Carolina Provincial Congress appoints a Council of Safety to handle the military affairs of the colony and to procure and distribute arms, powder, provisions, etc. The committee consisted of Henry Laurens, Charles Pinckney, Rawlins Lowndes, Thomas Ferguson, Miles Brewton, Arthur Middleton, Thomas Heyward, Jr., Thomas Bee, John Huger, James Parsons, William Henry Drayton, Benjamin Elliott, and William Williamson.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item> 
		<item>
			<date>Sept. 15, 1775</date>
			<title>Royal Governor Flees Charlestown</title>
			<desc>Fearing For his life, Royal Gov. Campbell flees From his home on Meeting Street to the HMS Tamar anchored in Charlestown harbor.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item> 
		<item>
			<date>Nov. 11, 1775</date>
			<title>Ships Exchange Fire in Harbor</title>
			<desc>William Henry Drayton personally supervises the scuttling of hulks in the Cooper River to remove the possibility that British warships might bombard the city. The HMS Tamar and HMS Cherokee fire and Drayton orders his ship to return fire. The first shots of the Revolutionary War in South Carolina occur.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item> 
		<item>
			<date>February 9, 1776</date>
			<title>Gadsden Presents New Flag</title>
			<desc>Christopher Gadsden presents his flag to the South Carolina Provincial Congress. The flag features a coiled rattlesnake and the phrase "Don't Tread On Me".</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>May, 1776</date>
			<title>Clinton's Fleet Arrives</title>
			<desc>Panic sweeps through the city at the first offshore sighting of a British armada. The ships carry over 3,000 British regulars.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>June 28, 1776</date>
			<title>Patriots Defend Charlestown</title>
			<desc>A British Force commanded bv Sir Peter Parker. began a long awaited attack on Charlestown. South Carolina troops in a small fort on Sullivan's Island engaged the British ships in a fierce artillery duel as they attempted to enter the harbor. Several British ships were badly damaged with heavy casulties, while suprisingly the fort built with palmetto logs and sand sustained little damage. The British were forced to abandon their plans to capture Charlestown For several years. The fort now known as Fort Moultrie bears the name of Colonel William Moultrie who supervised the building of the fort and commanded the troops who defended it.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		

		<item>
			<date>January 11, 1775</date>
			<title>Provincial Congress Forms</title>
			<desc>The First Provincial Congress is formed when representatives from throughout the state gather at the Exchange Building. They begin to establish a new government for the colony.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>June 3, 1775</date>
			<title>Provincial Congress Vows to Fight</title>
			<desc>The members of the Provincial Congress vote unanimously to adopt the Association and call upon all Carolinians to sign it. They pledge to unite themselves in the defense of their state. The Association was published in the South Carolina Gazette and Country Journal June 6, 1775</desc>
			<img>ATTACH 2B AS IMAGE</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>June 18, 1775</date>
			<title>Last Royal Governor Arrives</title>
			<desc>The last Royal Governor, Lord William Campbell, takes command. He is greeted with "sullen silence," a stark contrast from the boisterous welcome given to previous royal governors. As was customary, the local militia are assembled to meet him. Only this time they are assembled with the permission of the Council of Safety.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>Nov. 1, 1775</date>
			<title>Second Provincial Congress Elects Drayton President</title>
			<desc>Second Provincial Congress convenes in Charlestown. William Henry Drayton is elected president, displacing the more conservative Henry Laurens.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>Nov. 9, 1775</date>
			<title>Drayton Warns British Ship Captain</title>
			<desc>Members of the Provincial Congress fear that Charlestown might be bombarded as cities along the New England coast, especially Bristol in Rhode Island, had been during September and October. The congress directs Drayton to write this communication to the British commander of the HMS Tarnarthen anchored in Charlestown harbor.</desc>
			<img>ATTACH 5B AS IMAGE</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>Feb 11, 1776</date>
			<title>Provincial Congress Draws Up Constitution</title>
			<desc>Provincial Congress appointed a committee of eleven prominent men to draw up a plan of government.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>


		<item>
			<date>March, 1776</date>
			<title>First State Constitution Adopted</title>
			<desc>John Rutledge submitted to the Provincial Congress a proposed constitution for the State of South Carolina. The constitution was accepted and John Rutledge was elected first President and Commander-in-chief. Henry Laurens was elected Vice-President and William Henry Drayton, Chief Justice. </desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>August  2, 1776</date>
			<title>Colonies Declare Independence</title>
			<desc>The Declaration of Independence is signed in Philadelphia. South Carolina signers include Arthur Middleton, Edward Rutledge, Thomas Lynch, Jr., and Thomas Heyward, Jr.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>August  5, 1776</date>
			<title>Charlestown Celebrates Independence</title>
			<desc>News of the adoption of the Declaration of Independence reaches Charlestown triggering bonfires, parades, and a two day stoppage of business. The Declaration is read under the Liberty Tree by Maj. Barnard Elliot.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>August 11, 1777</date>
			<title>Tennent Dies</title>
			<desc>Rev. William Tennent dies at the High Hills of the Santee.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>Nov. 1, 1777</date>
			<title>Henry Laurens Elected President</title>
			<desc>Henry Laurens is elected president of the Continental Congress and serves in that position until December 9, 1778.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>March 5, 1778</date>
			<title>Rutledge Resigns Over Constitution Question</title>
			<desc>John Rutledge resigns as the state's president in a dispute concerning whether the Legislature had the right to change the state's constitution. Arthur Middleton is elected to succeed him, but he also declines being unwilling to approve the new constitution.  Rawlins Lowndes is elected president of the state.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>March 19, 1778</date>
			<title>Anglican Church Dissolved</title>
			<desc>SC adopts her second state constitution. The Church of England is disestablished.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>March 28, 1778</date>
			<title>Constituton Calls For Loyalty Oath</title>
			<desc>A law is passed under the new constitution demanding an oath of loyalty to the state of South Carolina.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>August 30, 1778</date>
			<title>Gadsden Fights Duel</title>
			<desc>A duel is fought between Christopher Gadsden and Maj. Gen. R. Howe. It is supposed to take place under the Liberty tree, but there are so many people around and in the tree that it is moved to “Mr. Percy's land.” The duel begins with each man staring at the other For several seconds through their pistol sights. In the end, Howe grazes Gadsden's ear, while Gadsden fires deliberately wide.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>Jan 9, 1779</date>
			<title>Rutledge Elected First Governor</title>
			<desc>John Rutledge was elected as the First governor of SC. He assumed dictatorial powers to facilitate defense preparations to meet an inevitable British attack.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>Sept. 1779</date>
			<title>Drayton Dies</title>
			<desc>William Henry Drayton dies in Philadelphia while attending a session of the Continental Congress.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>Feb. 3, 1780</date>
			<title>Charlestown Readies For British</title>
			<desc>Learning of the British advance on Charlestown, the SC Assembly meeting in the city at the time give Governor Rutledge extraordinary powers to "keep up an organization of the government." These powers are to last until ten days after the next meeting of the legislature. During this time, the governor is called "Dictator" Rutledge by many citizens unhappy with the arrangernent.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>


		<item>
			<date>July 1, 1776</date>
			<title>The Cherokees Attack the Southern Frontier</title>
			<desc>Incited by the royal agents John Stuart and Alexander Cameron, the powerful Cherokee Nation struck along the entire southern frontier killing men, women, and children and burning backcountry settlements. The Indian attack was meant to be coordinated with the attack on Fort Sullivan, but the great distances involved with resultant poor communications frustrated British planning. -- Lumpkin</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>July 15, 1776</date>
			<title>Lyndley's Fort, SC</title>
			<desc>A group of Patriot settlers who had taken refuge in Lyndley's Fort near Rabon Creek in Laurens County, SC, were attacked by Indians and Loyalists, some of the latter dressed as Indians. Reinforced by 150 militia, the settlers beat off and routed the attackers. -- Lumpkin</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>August 1, 1776</date>
			<title>Cherokees Ambush Williamson</title>
			<desc>Colonel Andrew Williamson, leading a punitive expedition against a band of Cherokees commanded by Alexander Cameron, was ambushed in the early morning of 1 August by superior Indian Forces. Williamson's men retreated in confusion but the day was saved for his little army by Colonel Leroy Hammond, who with a few followers led a mounted charge that checked the Indian advance. Francis Salvador was killed in this action, the first Jew to die For American freedom. -- Lumpkin</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>August, 1776</date>
			<title>Pickens Holds off Cherokees</title>
			<desc>Andrew Pickens, leading a scouting party of 25 men, was surprised and surrounded by 200 Cherokee warriors. Forming a circle, Pickens and his scouts loaded and fired in turn, successfully holding off a hand-to-hand attack until Joseph Pickens, Andrews brother, arrived with a volunteer rescue Force. -- Lumpkin</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>August 10, 1776</date>
			<title>Cherokees defeated</title>
			<desc>The Cherokees were defeated by Andrew Pickens, whose contingent suffered no casualties in a skirmish on the Tugaloo River. AFter the fighting the Indian towns of Estatoe and Tugaloo were razed to the ground. -- Lumpkin</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>August 12, 1776</date>
			<title>Cherokee Town Burned</title>
			<desc>Andrew Williamson and Andrew Pickens leading the full expeditionary force met and defeated a large Cherokee war party near the Indian town of Tamassy. Both sides suffered casualties, but the Indian losses were twice those of the South Carolinians. The town of Tamassy then was burned.  --Lumpkin</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>May 2O, 1777</date>
			<title>Cherokees Finally defeated</title>
			<desc>After suffering a succession of defeats and burning of many of their towns east and west of the mountains with the destruction of all food supplies, the Cherokees sued for peace. American casualties among the South Carolina, Virginia, and Georgia troops involved were in the low hundreds. The Indians lost over 2,000 killed and ceded most of their lands east of the mountains. --Lumpkin</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>


		<item>
			<date>Dec. 29, 1775</date>
			<title>British Capture Savannah</title>
			<desc>With the war at a stalemate in the North, the British planned a southern strategy. A British Fleet sailed up the Savannah River and landed Colonel Archibald Campbell with 3,000 crack British regulars and Provincials below Savannah, Ga. This little army attacked and defeated the American General Robert Howe, attempting to defend the town with 700 Continentals and militia. Savannah fell the same day. --Lumpkin</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>Mar. 29 - May 12, 1780</date>
			<title>Sir Henry Clinton's Siege of Charleston</title>
			<desc>Major General Sir Henry Clinton invested Charleston, SC, with formal siege approaches in March 1780. Admiral Mariot Arbuthnot ran the forts at the harbor entrance on April 8 and brought the guns of the royal fleet on the city, and Maj. Gen. Charles Lord Cornwallis closed off all escape across the Cooper River. When Clinton's advanced siege parallels reached the assault distance, Benjamin Lincoln on May 12 surrendered the town and his entire army. -- Lumpkin</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>May 29, 1780</date>
			<title>Buford's Massacre Shocks South</title>
			<desc>Colonel Abraham Buford retreating northward with Virginia Continentals after the fall of Charleston was overtaken by Lt. Col. Banastre Tarleton and his Loyalists Legion. Tarleton charged and Buford tried to surrender after the first American volley but in the confusion some of his men still resisted. The Loyalist dragoons and supporting light infantry ignored the flags of truce and sabered or bayoneted 113 Continentals while wounding 150, a total of 263 casualties out of 350. It was known thereafter to the Americans as Buford's Massacre. -- Lumpkin </desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>June 1, 1780</date>
			<title>Militia Accepts Clinton Pardon</title>
			<desc>Clinton offers to pardon all who submit and to punish severely all still in rebellion. The militia around Beaufort ask that Clinton accept them as prisoners on parole on the same terms as Charlestown and militia near Camden meet with Lord Rawdon with a similar request. Rebels in the Ninety-Six District also surrender on similar terms.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>June 3, 1780</date>
			<title>Clinton Abolishes Parole</title>
			<desc>Clinton issues a proclamation which abolishes the status of prisoners on parole for all except those who were actually part of the Charlestown garrison. Other prisoners on parole would be considered enemies unless they swore allegiance to the king. As such they could be required to fight as British subjects against the Patriots.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>June 5, 1780</date>
			<title>Clinton Congratulated</title>
			<desc>Several citizens of Charlestown present addresses of congratulations to Clinton and Arbuthnot. Patriot leaders are returning to Charlestown to submit.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>August 16, 1780</date>
			<title>Battle of Camden, SC</title>
			<desc>Horatio Gates with his American Army of the South and Lord Cornwallis commanding the British forces in South Carolina fought a "meeting" battle near Gum Swamp and Sanders Creek on the Old Waxhaws Road a few miles from Camden. Gate's army was defeated and routed, although Baron de Kalb and his Maryland and Delaware Continental troops on the American right resisted to the end. Gates fled the field but de Kalb was mortally wounded. -- Lumpkin</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>


		<item>
			<date>May 12, 1780</date>
			<title>Rutledge Escapes Charleston</title>
			<desc>Charleston surrendered, however several leaders were not captured, having been outside the city when it was captured. John Rutledge escaped at night and fled to North CaLolina.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>August  27, 1780</date>
			<title>Prominent Patriots Imprisoned</title>
			<desc>Twenty-nine prominent Charlestonians. including Christopher Gadsden, are arrested by British troops during the night. They are accused of encouraging resistance to British authority and imprisoned in the dungeon of the Old Exchange. They and others are later shipped to St. Augustine. Only those who sign an Oath of Loyalty to the Crown are released.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>August  4, 1781</date>
			<title>Isaac Hayne Hanged For Breaking Parole</title>
			<desc>In an effort to quell patriot resistance, the British hang local patriot Col. Isaac Hayne For breaking his parole. AFter the surrender of Charlestown to the British in 1780, Hayne was paroled and returned to his plantation. In 1781, the British authorities demanded that he either come to Charlestown as a prisoner or swear an oath of allegiance to the King. Because his wife and children were sick with smallpox and he did not want to leave them. Hayne chose to take the oath under the condition that he would never be asked to join the British military. Despite assurances from British officials that this condition would be kept, he was soon ordered to join the British army. Hayne felt that this action by the British relieved him of his oath, so he rejoined the South Carolina militia. He was captured while leading a raiding party on Charlestown Neck by Maj. Thomas Fraser of the Royal South Carolina Rangers and his command, and was brought back to Charlestown. Although Hayne was never properly tried, Lord Rawdon, commander of Charlestown, charged him with espionage and treason; later, Hayne was given a death sentence despite protests by local citizens. According to eye-witnesses, he met his death "with a firm step and serene aspect." Afterwards, Isaac Hayne became a martyr of the American fight For freedom and his name was used as a rallying cry by his fellow South Carolinians.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>February 26, 1782</date>
			<title>Loyalist Estates Conﬁscated</title>
			<desc>The estates of many loyalists are conﬁscated by the SC Legislature.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>

	
		<item>
			<date>July 30, 1780</date>
			<title>Partisans Continue the Fight</title>
			<desc>General Francis Marion and General Thomas Sumter who evaded capture at Charleston, along with General Andrew Pickens, who broke his parole after the British raided his plantation, organized partisan fighters who played a key role in defeating the British in the South.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>July 30, 1780</date>
			<title>Thomas Sumter at Rocky Mount</title>
			<desc>Thomas Sumter arrived with a strong force beFore the British post at Rocky Mount held by the Loyalist Lt. Col. George Turnbull. Summoned to surrender, Turnbull refused, and Sumter launched his attack. The main fortified area was a frame house internally reinForced by logs and clays. An almost successFul attempt to fire the frame house by hurling fire brands on the roof of an adjacent building was frustrated when a summer rainstorm extinguished the flames. Sumter retreated but lost a valued officer, LT. Col. Andrew Neel, killed in action. Seven of Sumter's soldiers were also killed. -- Lumpkin</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>August 25, 1780</date>
			<title>Francis Marion Frees Prisoners</title>
			<desc>Francis Marion, camped at Nelson or Neilson's Ferry on the Santee River north of Eutawville received information that 150 American prisoners taken at Camden were bivouacked For the night at Thomas Sumter's plantation, Great Savannah. Marion attacked, captured the British escort, and released the prisoners who refused to join him but continued to Charleston and internment.  -- Lumpkin</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>Sept. 28 - 29, 1780</date>
			<title>Battle of Black Mingo</title>
			<desc>Having learned that the Charleston Loyalist Col. John Corning Ball, with a strong force, was camped at Shepherd's Ferry on Black Mingo Creek, Francis Marion attacked with his partisans at midnight of Sept 28, driving Ball and his Loyalists into the swamp. Col. Ball escaped, but Marion captured his fine horse, which he renamed "Ball" and rode throughout the war. -- Lumpkin </desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>March 6, 1781</date>
			<title>Francis Marion at Wiboo Swamp</title>
			<desc>Wiboo Swamp was the first engagement in a series of savage retreating actions which Francis Marion conducted to obstruct the advance of a British column led by Col. John Watson. At Wiboo Swamp, Gavin James, a private in Marion's brigade, single-handedly held a narrow causeway until Marion and his partisans could withdraw safely into the swamp. -- Lumpkin</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>


		<item>
			<date>October 7, 1780</date>
			<title>Battle of Kings Mountain</title>
			<desc>The British officer Major Patrick Ferguson, with a force of around 800 North and South Carolina Loyalists supported by 100 of his Provincial rangers, was surrounded and attacked at Kings Mountain by approximately the same number of Frontier militia from North Carolina, South Carolina, Virginia, and Georgia. Most of the Americans were armed with the deadly long rifle. Ferguson died in the action, and almost all of his command was killed, wounded, or captured. This was a real American victory and one of the turning points of the Revolution. -- Lumpkin</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>December 3, 1780</date>
			<title>Nathanael Greene Assumes Command of the Southern Army</title>
			<desc>Maj. Gen. Nathanael Greene of Rhode Island assumed command of the American Army of the Southern Department replacing Horatio Gates. Making his temporary headquarters at Charlotte, NC, Greene began to make plans for a renewed offensive against Lord Cornwallis in South Carolina. -- Lumpkin</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>January 17, 1781</date>
			<title>Tarleton Badly Beaten at Cowpens</title>
			<desc>Brig. Gen. Daniel Morgan at Saunders Cowpens in upper South Carolina met and soundly defeated Lt. Col. Banastre Tarleton and his army of British regulars and well-trained provincials. The forces were about equal but the American army on that day was the better army and won. The British losses, particularly in light troops, were very heavy, and Cowpens should be considered the real turning point of the Revolution. The royal forces never fully recovered from this disaster. -- Lumpkin</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>March 15, 1781</date>
			<title>The Battle of GuilFord Court House, NC</title>
			<desc>Cornwallis, attacking with an inferior force Nathanael Greene's much stronger army holding a prepared position at GuilFord Court House, drove the Americans from the field. The British suffered such heavy losses in this pyrrhic victory that the royal army was forced to fall back on the coast. Greene retreated in good order, regrouped, and followed Cornwallis, then swung south and marched back to South Carolina. Cornwallis rested briefly at Wilmington, NC, and decided to move his operations to virginia. -- Lumpkin</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>June 6, 1781</date>
			<title>British Evacuate Georgetown</title>
			<desc>British forces, unable to maintain a proper defense of Georgetown, SC, against increasing American pressure, abandoned the town and evacuated by sea to Charleston. -- Lumpkin</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>October 19, 1781</date>
			<title>Cornwallis Surrenders at Yorktown, VA</title>
			<desc>Brigadier Charles O'Hara of the Guards led out Yorktown's British garrison and surrendered to Washington and Rochambeau 7,157 soldiers including 2,000 sick and wounded in the town's hospitals, 840 sailors, and 80 camp followers. George Washington was victorious at last. fighting continued For another year, but the loss of the army at Yorktown doomed the British war effort in North America to defeat. -- Lumpkin</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>December 15, 1781</date>
			<title>Loyalists Promised Protection</title>
			<desc>Proclamation is issued by Alexander Leslie, Lieutenant-General and commander of the British Forces in the Southern District. It is later placed on the front page of every issue of the Royal Gazette. --Read Proclamation</desc>
			<img>ATTACH 7B AS IMAGE</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>March 20, 1782</date>
			<title>British Seek Negotiations</title>
			<desc>Lord North is replaced by Lord Rockingham as British Prime Minister. Rockingham seeks negotiations with the American peace commissioners.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>September 27, 1782</date>
			<title>Negotiations in Paris</title>
			<desc>Formal negotiations of peace began in Paris, France. British commander Sir Carleton moves British troops towards New York to ready For departure.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>November 30, 1782</date>
			<title>Preliminary Treaty Signed</title>
			<desc>A preliminary peace treaty is signed in Paris. Terms include recognition of American independence and the boundaries of the United States, along with British withdrawal F=from America.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>December 14, 1782</date>
			<title>British Evacuation of Charleston, SC</title>
			<desc>On December 14 Maj. Gen. Alexander Leslie, commanding British Forces in South Carolina, withdrew his troops from the advanced works on the Charleston peninsula and marched them down to Gadsden's wharf at the foot of what is now Calhoun Street, where the soldiers were embarked. At eleven o'clock in the morning on the same day American troops led by General Anthony Wayne occupied Charleston. -- Lumpkin</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>February 4, 1783</date>
			<title>Armistice Agreed To</title>
			<desc>Britain proclaimed a cessation of hostilities and a general armistice was finally made.</desc>
			<img>Reminder</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
		<item>
			<date>Sept. 3, 1783 </date>
			<title>Treaty of Peace signed</title>
			<desc>Formal Peace Treaty is signed in Paris.</desc>
			<img>ATTACH 13b THROUGH 13H -- FULL TEXT of PEACE TREATY</img>
			<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
		</item>
</items> 
