
<items>
	<item>
		<date>1750</date>
		<title>Incident Touches Off War</title>
		<desc>A savage war with the Cherokees was touched oFF aFter an incident at Ft. Prince where an English Army officer was wounded. Cherokee hostages were killed in cold blood and all hope For negotiations ended.</desc>
		<img>Reminder</img>
		<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
	</item>
	<item>
		<date>April 1750</date>
		<title>British Army Arrives to Protect Province</title>
		<desc>Gov. William Bull Jr. requests help. About 1,200
British regulars arived under Col. Archibald
Montgomery. Thev relieved Ft. Prince aFter a
campaign oF burning villages. Montgomery then was
ordered bacl-c north leaving a small Force For local
defense.</desc>
		<img>Reminder</img>
		<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
	</item>
	<item>
		<date>1751</date>
		<title>British Send Troops Again</title>
		<desc>When Fort Loudoun surrendered to the
Cherokees, man',r oF the garrison were I-cilled
and the rest tal-cen prisoner. This reopening
oF the war prompted another request For
help. Col. James Grant responded with
1.600 men under his command. A Force oF
over 1,000 provincials joined with these
British regulars and eventually deFeated the
Cherol-cees.</desc>
		<img>Reminder</img>
		<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
	</item>
	<item>
		<date>1753</date>
		<title>War Doubles Britan's Debt
Colonies Asked to Pay Their Share</title>
		<desc>The conclusion oF the French and Indian War, or Seven
Years War, resulted in a deFinite change in British-colonial
relations. The Treat"; oF Paris in 1363 aFFirmed Britain"s
undisputed control oF the seas and shipping trade. It also
aFFirmed its sovereignty over much oF the North American
continent east oF the Mississippi River. However, the British
had gone deeplv in debt to Finance the war. Having
borrowed heavilv From British and Dutch banl-cers the
national debt almost doubled From £?5 million in 1354 to
£1.33 million in 1363. To raise the necessary Funds to retire
the debt British oFFicials turned to increasing import duties
and ta>ces on goods lil-ce sugar, tobacco, salt, beer, spirits,
etc. Given that a portion oF the debt was due to Britain
deFending the North American colonies during the war, the
British government Felt that the colonies were obligated to
_sh_ar_e the costs o_F deFending the empire.</desc>
		<img>Reminder</img>
		<img-cap>blah</img-cap>
	</item>
</items>